Guide to the John E. Nance papers, 1960-1990.
Nance, John E. papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
John E. Nance papers, 1960-1990.
6909
Nance, John,
40 cubic feet.
Research material
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Records documenting the research of John Nance on the Tasaday people of the Philippines and his coverage of the Vietnam War. Formats include notes, published material, audio tapes and transcripts, video cassettes and photographic prints, negatives and slides.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
John Edwards Nance (1935-2010) was a writer, journalist, and photographer, most famous for his work on the Tasaday people of the Philippines.
After graduating from the University of Oregon in 1957, Nance became a journalist with the Associated Press, reporting from Vietnam (1965-1967) and elsewhere, including as the AP Bureau Chief for Manila (1968-1972).
In 1971, he was among the few journalists and anthropologists allowed to meet the newly discovered Tasaday people. The Tasaday became the subject of much of the rest of his life's work. He wrote books about them, including The Gentle Tasaday (1975), Lobo of the Tasaday (1982) and Discovery of the Tasaday: a photo novel (1981). He also edited a volume of essays on the Tasaday, entitled Further Studies on the Tasaday.
When a controversy emerged in the late 1980's, alleging that the Tasaday people were a hoax propagated by Philippine politicians, Nance became an ardent defender of the Tasaday, arguing for their legitimacy as an autonomous group.
Nance also published books including The land and people of the Philippines (1977) and The mud-pie dilemma: a Master Potter's Struggle to Make Art and Ends Meet (1978).
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Records documenting the research of John Nance on the Tasaday people of the Philippines and his coverage of the Vietnam War. Formats include notes, published material, audio tapes and transcripts, video cassettes and photographic prints, negatives and slides.
While this collection contains some material on Vietnam and environmental causes, the majority consists of Nance's work regarding the Tasaday. This includes primary research from his many visits with the Tasaday, including notebooks, photographs, audio recordings, and transcripts of interviews with members of the Tasaday people. It also includes additional secondary research on the Philippines and the Tasaday, particularly during the controversy over the Tasaday's existence. Drafts of Nance's books are also in the collection.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Nance, John, 1935-
Subjects:
Tasaday (Philippine people); Tasaday (Philippine people) -- Social life and customs.; Tasaday (Philippine people) -- Public opinion.; Impostors and imposture -- Philippines.; Vietnam War, 1961-1975.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I: Research
Nance’s notes and transcripts from his visits with the Tasaday. Also includes articles (subject files) and notes Nance used in his work, on topics ranging from the Tasaday to environmentalism to Vietnam.
Series II: Photographic materials
Primarily photographs of Tasaday, the Philippines and Vietnam. Includes black and white and color photographs, slides, negatives and contact sheets.
Series III. Video
Includes videos on the Tasaday. VHS, DVD and film.
Series IV. Audio
Includes recordings of Nance’s interviews with Tasaday, and other audio related audio material. On cassette and microcassette.
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I: Research
  Nance’s notes and transcripts from his visits with the Tasaday. Also includes articles (subject files) and notes Nance used in his work, on topics ranging from the Tasaday to environmentalism to Vietnam.
  - Sustainability of Life, 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - IRRI/OSU, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Worldwide Forestry, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Conservation Folder 1: Conservation International, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Conservation Folder 2: Ecotrust, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Tropical Forest Forever, 1987-1992 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - "The Invention of Culture" Material, 1988-1993 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Conservation Folder A: Global Issues Resource Center, 1986-1988 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Conservation Folder B: Rainforests of the World, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Conservation Folder C: Newsletters, 1987-1989 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - 1971 Tasaday Data: Elizalde-Fox report in Smithsonian, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Biodiversity/Conservation Research, 1987-1989 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Undated Notebooks Part 1, [N.D.] (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Undated Notebooks Part 2, [N.D.] (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 1972 Notebooks Part 1, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 1972 Notebooks Part 2, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - 1974 Notebooks, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Loose Notes on Tasaday, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Photos 1, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Philippine Forests in Danger, 1985-1989 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - New Tasaday Notes-March to April 3, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Notes for Tasaday Fiction Book, [N.D.] (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Notes for Lobo Fiction Book, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - A Tasaday Folio by J. Bailen, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Tasaday Controversy, 1987-1989 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Latest News Clippings/J.Bailen, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Dula-Banas Interviews by Mai Tuan, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Jerome Bailen's Curriculum Vitae, [after 1982?] (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Tasaday Revisited by J. Peralta, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Rethinking the Tasaday Controversy by Maria Elena Lopez, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Packing List, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - People v. Franklin Tañedo for Qualified Theft, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Sunday Inquirer Magazine, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Manuel Elizalde, Jr. Clearances, 1987-1988 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - List of Stone Tools, [N.D.] (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Congressional Committee Report with note, [1987?] (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Affidavits, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Salazar Genealogical Chart 1986, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Letter to Manuel Elizalde, Jr. From Father Raymundo Hilot-Executive Secretary Episcopal Commission on Tribal Filipinos, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Museum Paper/Amor Ramos Affidavits of Dad Tuan and Jun Casquejo, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Philippine Daily Globe-Central Television Newspaper Item, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Description-Agricultural Stone Tool-Grinder/Pounder (shown in Tape No. 3), [N.D.] (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Solicitation of Funds-Jerome Bailen, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Salazar Genealogical Chart 1988, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Various Affidavits, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Salazar U.P. Note with Guide in English, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Sarangani Journal, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - AAA Letters Post TX, 1988-1989 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Boone, Eliezer, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Packing List 2, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Packing List 3, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Packing List 4, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Packing List 5, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Packing List 6, [after 1986?] (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Packing List 7, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Packing List 8, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Packing List 9, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Packing List 10, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Packing List 11, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Packing List 12, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Judith Moses Letter, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Tribesmen Interviewed Re: Tasaday Question (Tapes 1 & 2), [N.D.] (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Copies of Anthropology Studies, 1978-1988 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Clippings from 1980, 1988, 1980, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Other Materials (Manuel Elizalde and PANAMIN), 1969 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - "Authorities Cited in Fernandez Testimony" (Forest-Pastells), 1971-1973 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - The Sunday Times Magazine, 1971-1988 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Newspapers, 1980-1989 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Tasaday Genealogies and Language (Amy Rara's Info), 1980-1988 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Contract Signing with Cardinal Sin Regarding Channel 11 TV Station, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Louie (Vera) Reyes, Mail/Contract, 1974-1983 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Tas Correspondence U.S. 1977-1982, 1978-1979 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Philippine Studies Bulletin, 1977-1983 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Philippine Studies -Scholars, 1985-1989 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Stone Age Tour/Message From the Stone Age, 1982-1984 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Speech, Script, Editorial Notes on Message From the Stone Age, 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Oct Finance/Bills for Message From Stone Age, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Magazines with Tasaday Articles, 1972-1981 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Magazines 2, 1968-1972 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Magazine 3, with notes and contract, 1967-1993 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Tasaday Magazines, 1972-1995 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - US Bank Statements. Misc to Deposit and Madame w/D etc, 1971-1984 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Writing Notes for Tasaday Book 1991, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Tasaday-Quotes saved in 1991, 1979-1992 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - A-Newsclips on Phil-1991, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - B- Anthropology, Sociology Relevant to Tasaday, 1972-1990 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - C-Relevant News Articles 1991-Environment, tribes, demographics, women-man's issues, 1986-1992 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - D-Notes re Tas 1991, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Life Magazine, 1955-1990 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Cosmopolitan-Germany, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - 1988 Clippings on the Tasaday (October), 1988 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - 1988 Clippings on the Tasaday (September), 1988 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - 1988 Clippings on the Tasaday (March), 1988 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - 1988 Clippings on the Tasaday (January), 1988 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - 1987 Clippings on the Tasaday (December), 1987 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - 1987 Clippings on the Tasaday (November), 1987 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - 1987 Clippings on the Tasaday (October), 1987 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - 1987 Clippings on the Tasaday (September), 1987 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - 1987 Clippings on the Tasaday (August), 1987 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - 1987 Clippings on the Tasaday (July), 1987 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Nance Tasaday Talk Newspaper Articles, 1984-1986 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Nance Tasaday Talk Flyers, 1983-1986 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Nance Tasaday Talk Miscellaneous, 1981-1986 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Data XIII Genealogy, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Gen Data XV b/c/d/e/f, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Headland response to Amy Ro-Ra genealogy paper 1990, 1989-1990 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Genealogy Data I, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - JN Tasaday Notes for 1993, 1989-1993 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Tropical Forest Biosphere Reserve Proposal to C.I., 1985-1993 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Junny Kalaw (Maximo Kalaw Jr.), 1987-1989 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Conservation International-WX, 1990-1998 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - International Herald Tribune Newspaper, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - 1986 Tasaday Notes, 1986-1991 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Edith Terry Tasaday Notebook July 1971, 1971-1986 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Elizalde's M/S, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Feb 1982 Report to FM on UKA and Tao Makel, 1982-1986 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Photo Coverage of US President Gerald Ford's Visit to Philippines, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Ken MacLeish Nat Geo Tribes in Trouble, 1971-1972 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - JN Phil Trip 1980, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Encyclopedia Britannica Yearbook 1973 on Science and the Future, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Tas Misc 1971 to 85, 1974-1976 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - JEN Museum Papers/memos/etc 1973-75, 1974-1976 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Tas Notes, Correspondence for Book Possibility, 1971-1983 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - 1976 Further Studies on TS, 1974-1975 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Philippine Tribal Connections, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Nance Footage, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Smithsonian Report, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - The ESQ Rhum Controversy by J. Bailen, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Brief Notes on Threatened Ecosystems in Mindanao: Two Case Studies by Juan R. Francisco (1976), 1976 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Photos of Datu Dudim and Mafalo, [N.D.] (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - International Festival Brochure, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Panamin Board of Trustees, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Provincial Profiles of Region XI, [after 1987?] (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Tape Translation, [N.D.] (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Transcription of Datu Galang's Stock Shots (Tape 2), [N.D.] (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Copy of Tasaday Lawsuit v. Professors, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Mandaya Tribe Book, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - The Tasaday Controversy: An Assessment of the Evidence, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - A Genealogical Study of the Tasaday Forest People of Mindanao Island, Philippines, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Datu Dudim Bilagan, [N.D.] (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Elizer Boone, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Biosphere Reserves in Amazon Heidi Ramsour, 1988-1989 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - People in the Tropical Forest PSU/Forestry Center 26 April 89, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Philippine Eagle Conservation Program, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Fern Fox-1986, Sept 86, Oct., 1986 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Radio Messages re Tasaday Discovery 7 June to 30 June 1971, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Tasaday notes, Elizalde articles/speech, 1970-1971 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Southeast Asia Chronicle. Tribal People and Marcos/PANAMIN by Joel Rocamora, 1979-1986 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - ECTF "Research Papers", 1981-1984 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Anti-Slavery Society in Philippines, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - 1991 Tasaday Data, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Facts About the Tasaday Controversy, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Tas Odds and Ends/Miscellaneous 1988, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - 1988 Tasaday Clippings from Doreen Fernandez, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Tasaday Loose Notes for 1988, 1986-1988 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - JN Tasaday Loose Notes 1988, 1987-1989 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Interviews with Tasaday 1988, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Zagreb Anthro Conference July 1988, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - 1988 Congressional Committee Report on Tasaday, 1987-1988 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Central Independent TV-"Scandal", 1988-1989 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Anti-Tasaday Papers/Docs, 1981-1988 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Datu Galang-1988-1989-Budget for Tubac, 1988-1989 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Various Affidavits, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Background to Tas Legal Suit 1988 and Copy of Suit, 1986-1988 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - PB and Dwight, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - 1988 MEJR-For Sycip, Salaz, or Law Office, 1986-1988 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - American Indian Tribe Legal Cases Re: Tasaday Relevance-Preston Brown Sep 88, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Tribal Meeting in Manila Nov 22-27 '88 News Articles, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - International Festival on Indigenous Cultures Conference Kit, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Tasaday Notes/stories Re Nov '88 International Tribal Festival and Conference in Manila, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - News Releases Written Manila 1988, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Tasaday Clippings 1988, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Edith Terry-Toronto Globe and Mail 6 June to Nov 1989, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - AAA Articles and Letters 1989, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - AAA Meeting on Tas-Washington DC 1989 Nov, 1989-1990 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - OVT Re PANAMIN/ME jr./Kalinga Oct 6/7 1989, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Edit-TV/Video work on Tasaday 1989, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Tasaday Com. Care Foundation, [N.D.] (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Santa Cruz Mission/Fr Rex 1988-1989, 1987-1989 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - AAA Prelims, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - T'boli Municipality 74, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Writing Freelance, 1974-1975 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Nance Philippine Trip 1980, 1979-1980 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Data Re Black and White Print for Discovery of Tasaday-taken 1980, [after 1975?] (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Chris-Rose-Via com Kinsolving: Film of Tasaday 1983-1985, 1983-1985 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Tasaday-JEN/PD notes Nov/Dec '85, Jan '86, 1984-1986 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Raw Stuff and Billings on Message Brochure, [after 1983?] (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Loose Material, 1978-1982 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Message From the Stone Age brochures, [after 1983?] (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Tasaday articles and book cover drafts, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - "Dispeller of Darkness" Nance Article, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Molony Papers from CM 2 Apr 93, 1977-1993 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Loose Notes, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Carol Molony data Rec'd Apr 93, 1987-1993 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Tasaday Magazines 1, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Tasaday Magazines 2, 1972-1989 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Tasaday Magazines 3, 1991-1998 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Tasaday Magazine and Nance Open Letter, 1986-1989 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Tasaday books and magazine, 1975-1977 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Tas-Quotes in 1991, 1979-1991 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Tasaday related Articles 1991 File, 1982-1991 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Stone Age in general, 1966-1986 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - World Wildlife Fund Newsletter, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - WBEZ Tasaday Stuart Rosenberg-Discussion 1991, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Cory Aquino Statement on Tasaday, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Random Papers on the Tasaday, 1986-1989 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Notes Dec 87-U.S., 1987 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - British Central TV 1987 San Luis Obispo California, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Asiaweek Tasaday 1987, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - 1987 Tasaday Notes, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Klinteberg, Robt May 1987, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - 1986 Tasaday and the Church-Sta Cruz Mission/Cardinal Sin, 1986-1990 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - JN re Tas 1986-notes in Portland re hearing Iten accusations/talk with Yen, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Oscar Trinidad/Tony Cervantes notes-1st Trip- 1986, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Tas Notes/1986 MLA-1st Trip: JN notes-Peralta Report/Oswald Iten phone notes, Cask? For CRISPO, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - 1986 Tasaday (News clips), 1986 (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Jess Peralta notes on Tao Makel-pre-Tas visit '86, 1983-1987 (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Carlos Fernandez 1986, 1977-1986 (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - Cervantes, Tony, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - Tasaday '86 Comments to be filed by name, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - Tasaday-UP '86 Manila Conference, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - Magazines, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - 1990 Tasaday Data, 1983-1990 (Box 7, Folder 43)
  - "International Affairs" Magazines, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 44)
  - 1991 Tas File. Books. Articles. Quotes., 1987-1992 (Box 7, Folder 45)
  - Psychology Perspectives 1992, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 46)
  - Cognitive Anthology: Sylvia Scribner Papers AAA 1992, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 47)
  - Accountant/Financial Advisor, 1991-1992 (Box 7, Folder 48)
  - Media Tas File 1992, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 49)
  - Readings on the Tasaday, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Summary-News clippings '86, '87, '88 Col. Guerrero, [after 1988?] (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - M. Mondragon (re Blit) 12 May '89-statement re his life and forest, 1989-1992 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - M. Elizalde notes, articles, comments 1989, 1988-1989 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Elizalde 1989, 1987-1989 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Manda 1989-phone to JEN Jan-May 1989, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Papers-ex. Steve L., 1979-1985 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Tas-Odds and Ends/Notes 1989, 1988-1989 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Judith Moses-Tina Luz 1989, 1966-1989 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - 1988/89 Ex-Manila Fax File, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - PANAMIN and BG Chico R. Kalinga, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - JN/Tas RP "Loose Notes-89", 1988-1989 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Loose Notes for 1989, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Philippines Clipping 1989, 1987-1989 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - News Clippings 1989 Manila/etc., 1989 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Tasaday Court Case July '89, 1988-1989 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Susan Hurley/Odell/Heitner, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Sta. Cruz Mission-Interviews with Mission Staff for Tasaday May 1988, Acq. by JN 1989--Oct?, 1988-1989 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Tasaday Papers at AAA Mtg, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Mindanao Gazette 1989, 1988-1989 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - TS Notes 1987. Manila 31 Oct to 18 Nov 87, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Loose Notes 19 to 31 Nov '87, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Field Notes Manila December 1987, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Tas Misc. 1987, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - News Clips 1987 Jan to December, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - News Clips 1987 Jan to December, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Elizalde talks re Costa Rica, syndicate. News clips on ME Jr ex Manila Aug-Sep 1987, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Tanduay Takeover Tried, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Encyclopedia Britannica Papers Oct 16 to Dec 29 '87, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - National Geo Said to Deny Tasaday 1987, UP release/Bailen, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Stories and Interview with Dula in Manila 1987, 1987-1988 (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Videos Sequenced: Congress Hearing 1987, Roger Arienda w/ Tas and logging 1987, JN-TS at Kematu 1988, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Transcripts of Tasaday Congressional Hrg 1987, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - 1987 Mai Tuan files said against Inquirer re stories he murdered E. Boone, 1987-1988 (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - Tasaday Cong. Hearing 1987, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Dula at Lake Sebu Congress Re Tas 1987, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - Philippine Military Intelligence Docs. Secret in Tasaday 1987-88, 1982-1987 (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - TS Jan-March 1987, 1986-1987 (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - Original Early Tasaday Articles and Info filed 2-'88. Mirro-Lozano-Iten-Salazar-Stern. 1971-hoax 86., 1986 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - 1986 Tasaday Documents, Clippings, Papers. June-July-Aug 19-1986, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Anti-Tasaday Statements/Papers by Oswald Iten, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Stern/Magazine re Tasaday, Translation, 1971-1986 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Peralta, Jess 1986 papers, 1971-1986 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Manila-1986-April-May-June notes, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - NBC/JEN to TS 1986 1st Trip w/ T. Cheatham? Contracts, bills, receipts, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - NBC-Data-Tapes etc-1986-Reynolds, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - 1986 T'boli: Dad Tuan/Blahiz/Mafalo/Dafal/Igna, Yanni, Mai, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Col. (Ret) Joey Guerrero and Peppito Gallego-Elizalde & co 1986, 1983-1986 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Notes Gerry Malayang File-TS/et al, Gerry Malayang 1986 Manila, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - J. Guerrero letter et al '79 to '84, 1979-1984 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Jerry Malayang 1986, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - "20/20" 1986, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - 1986 Tasaday UP Conference, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Tas Notes-MLA 1986, 1986 Aug-Sept/UP Conference Notes, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Tasaday magazine articles, 1967-1984 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Tasaday Magazine Articles 2, 1980-1990 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Survival International 1989/1990, 1989-1990 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - 1990 Articles, Letters, Notes, Miscellaneous, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Tas 1990 Papers/Notes JN, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Tasaday File 1992-News clips of general interest and relevance, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Philippines News Articles 1991, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - 1991 Indians Relevant to Tasaday, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Into the Heart- Kenneth Good, 1991-1992 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - JN Notes on Tasaday 1992, 1991-1992 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Articles with Specific Relevance to Tasaday 1991-1992, 1990-1993 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Tas File 1992 Rain Forests, 1992 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Articles on Tasaday/John Nance, 1969-1986 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Articles on Tasaday/John Nance, 1969-1986 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Articles on Tasaday/John Nance 2, 1968-1983 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - "Los Tasadays Cronica de Otro Planeta" en Los Domigos De ABC, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Duped or Superseded Genealogical Data, 1989? (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Dupe Data. Analysis of Genealogy, 1989 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Genealogical Data XV-a 1 to 5, 1989 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Genealogical Data XVI-JN notes, 1989-1992 (Box 10, Folder 12)